bluelaguna.net 2013-06-19

# Display Web User Privacy Policy | ValueClick Media

**Display Web User Privacy Policy**

_Updated as of_ _10_ _/_ _4_ _/2012_

Welcome to ValueClickMedia.com, a division of ValueClick, Inc. (hereinafter "ValueClick Media", “we” or “us”). All references to “ValueClick Media”, “we” or “us” in this Privacy Policy shall refer only to ValueClick Media excluding Lead Generation (as defined below).

At ValueClick Media, privacy is a top priority and we provide this Privacy Policy to outline our practices and procedures with respect to information collection and use to enable you to make an informed decision about sharing information with us. ValueClick Media is an advertising network which means we may deliver advertisements to the websites you visit.

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies solely to ValueClick Media, excluding ValueClick Media’s lead generation component (“Lead Generation”) which is addressed in a separate privacy policy linked as follows: [Click Here for Lead Generation’s privacy policy](http://www.valueclickmedia.com/about/privacy/lead-gen-web-user). All other ValueClick, Inc. entities are governed by separate privacy policies found on such entities’ websites.

ValueClick Media is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative which works to address important privacy and consumer protection issues in emerging media. For more information, please click here.

**INTRODUCTION**

**Acceptance of Terms.**  
Please read this policy carefully since by visiting this website (“Website”) and/or sharing information with us, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. The Privacy Policy may be revised or updated at any time by us. This page was last updated as of the date at the top of this Privacy Policy.

**Summary.**  
We have included a table summarizing our practices solely for your convenience and reference purposes. This table, however, is not an exhaustive description of our privacy practices and should not be construed to define, limit, or describe the scope or extent of our Privacy Policy. As a result, we urge you to read the entire document.

**Summary**

|   
---|---  
  
Information NOT Collected - PII

| 

We do not collect personally identifiable information (data collected with an intention to identify and contact a person such as name, address, telephone number or e-mail address) (hereinafter “PII”). However, the Lead Generation business does collect PII. More information on the collection of PII can be found on clicking on the following link to Lead Generation’s [privacy policy](http://www.valueclickmedia.com/about/privacy/lead-gen-web-user).  
  
Information Collected - Non-PII

| 

The non-personally identifiable information we collect may include as an example, IP address, browser types, operating systems, domain names, access dates and times, referring website addresses, online transactions and browsing and search activity. In the event any health-related information is collected, that data is anonymous and the health information is limited to these [health segments](http://www.valueclickmedia.com/hs).  
  
How Used

| 

We may use your Non-PII (“Information”) for the following general purposes: enhancement of our services, marketing, and to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests. Click on the link for more detailed information.  
  
Sharing Your Information

| 

We may share your Information with third party service providers we have contracted with, ValueClick, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates, including ValueClick Media (“Value Click Entities”), third party marketing partners, business partners and our clients.  
  
Your Choices

| 

You may regulate the collection of your Information through your browser settings or use of an "opt-out Cookie". Click on the link for more detailed information.  
  
Security

| 

We use reasonable and appropriate security measures to protect your data.  
  
Changes

| 

We may change the Privacy Policy at any time by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Website and if such changes are material, a notice of the changes will also be posted along with the revised Privacy Policy.  
  
Retention

| 

We retain Non-PII for use to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests for no more than eighteen (18) months. Aggregate Non-PII data for reporting may be retained for a longer period.  
  
Contact Us

| 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of or your dealings with us relating to this Privacy Policy, please fill out our [Feedback Form](http://www.valueclick.com/feedback?t=p&r=vcm-wpp01) or you can send correspondence to us at the following address: ValueClick Media, Privacy Officer, 30699 Russell Ranch Road, Suite 250, Westlake Village, CA 91362.  
  
**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information.**  
As part of our on-going efforts to ensure the best possible experience for all recipients of ValueClick Media advertising, we may use log files, web beacons and cookies to collect data from browsers, advertiser and third party sites (“Sites”) to aggregate Information. The Information collected is used for marketing purposes, enables us to determine which advertisements perform well, allows us to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests, assists us in improving the operation of our services, helps us to maintain the quality of our services, enhances our services to our business partners and clients and enables us to provide general statistics to our business partners and clients regarding use of ValueClick Media’s services.

“Log files” track actions occurring on Sites and collect data including, as an example, your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, click data and types of advertisements viewed.

"Web beacons" are electronic files used to track your navigation of a website or collection of sites, the completion of transactions, submittal of applications and browsing behavior.

"Cookies" are files (e.g. HTTP cookies) that are stored on your Internet enabled device (which may include, as an example, your computer, tablet, BlackBerry, smartphone or other PDA). Cookies are used to improve the experience web users have when they see web advertisements and ensure that when a web user clicks on an advertisement, they are sent to the correct click-through destination. We may use Cookies for purposes that include estimating the total reach of an advertising campaign, as well as frequency of display. This allows advertisers to determine with greater accuracy the composition of the audience they reach. Cookies may also be used to control the delivery of a series of advertisements to a web browser, and to limit the number of times a web browser receives any one advertisement.

There are two classes of Cookies based on how long they remain on your system: (i) “Session Cookies” are used only during your visit to the Sites and are erased once you close your browser, and (ii) “Persistent Cookies” remain on your browser for 2 years from your last visit to the Sites and enable us to remember you on subsequent visits to the Sites and provide more relevant content to you on such Sites.

There are many misconceptions about Cookies, some of which we will try to address in this policy. Cookies cannot erase your hard drive or otherwise damage your computer and do not tell us an e-mail address or any other PII. ValueClick Media does not and cannot use Cookies or web beacons to retrieve PII from your computer.

A useful resource on understanding Cookies may be found at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION**

**Information Shared by ValueClick Media.**  
ValueClick Media will only share your Information for the limited purposes provided for in this Privacy Policy. This includes sharing Information (1) to enable third party service providers to assist or facilitate in the services we provide to our clients; (2) to comply with applicable laws and regulations or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information received by Us, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (3) to enforce our terms of use or to protect our rights ; (4) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service; (5) with other ValueClick Entities and third party marketing partners (including advertisers and publishers) for marketing purposes; (6) with vendors, administrative service providers, technology providers, and carefully selected partners for data validation, enhancement, information verification and suppression services or (7) for any other purpose for which you provide consent. We also may share Information with advertisers, publishers and other third parties for marketing purposes, but such Information does not include PII. While ValueClick Media strongly encourages clients and partners to adopt responsible approaches to online marketing, ValueClick Media is not responsible for the information practices of such clients and partners. The collection, use, and disclosure of information by clients and partners are subject to their respective privacy policies, which may differ from this Privacy Policy.

In the event that ValueClick Media is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from you as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your Information is treated, transferred, or used.

**Information Collected by Third Party Sites.**  
Please be aware that the websites of our advertiser clients as well as the websites on which we place advertisements or any third party websites linked to one of our sites also may collect information from you. Such information may include non-personally identifiable information through the use of Cookies and other technology and any personally identifiable information you may choose to give in registering and transacting with such website. Although we choose our business partners and clients carefully, ValueClick Media is not responsible for the privacy practices of websites operated by such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of such websites you visit to determine how they handle any information they collect from you.

**YOUR CHOICES**

ValueClick Media also offers an “opt-out Cookie” to block the placement of future ValueClick Media Cookies on your system for 10 years from the time you opted out. If you have multiple internet browsers or users on the same computer or device, you will need to perform the opt-out operation for each browser, device and/or user. If you or your privacy software deletes the opt-out Cookie from your computer, browser or device, you will need to repeat the process.

Please note that the above link for an opt-out Cookie is only applicable to ValueClick Media and not any other ValueClick company or ValueClick company website. Also, please note that use of the opt-out Cookie will affect our ability to provide you content and advertisements that will more effectively match your interests and may prevent us from controlling the frequency with which you may view any particular advertisement. Please report any problems related to the opt-out process by filling out our [Feedback Form](http://www.valueclick.com/feedback?t=o&r=vcm-wpp02).

**PROCESSING AND STORING YOUR DATA**

FOR EUROPEAN UNION AND SWISS CITIZENS

The European Union ("EU") maintains strict privacy laws. These rules differ significantly from the laws of the United States of America (“U.S.”). To reconcile these differences, the US and the EU have created a safe harbor (“U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework”) that defines mutually acceptable privacy operations. The U.S. and Switzerland have created a similar safe harbor (“U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework”). For more information see <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

ValueClick Media complies with the U.S.-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view the company's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

In compliance with U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, we commit to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first fill out our [Feedback Form](http://www.valueclick.com/feedback?t=p&r=vcm-wpp02). 

ValueClick Media has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. Thus, if you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by ValueClick Media please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR website at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.

**Network Advertising Initiative.**  
ValueClick Media is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). The NAI is a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. For more information, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Security.**  
ValueClick Media employs appropriate measures to ensure the security of all Information and we routinely evaluate our practices to identify security threats or opportunities for the improvement of our services. No transmission of information is guaranteed to be completely secure. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise data security. You acknowledge and agree to assume this risk when communicating with us.

**CHANGES**

As the standards governing Internet privacy continue to evolve, ValueClick Media may find it appropriate or necessary to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. As a result, we reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time and shall post such changes on the Website. Our Website will state the date the Privacy Policy was last updated. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you use this Website to make sure you understand how your information will be used. If we materially change how we use your Information, we will notify via a prominent notice on the Website prior to implementing the change

**RETENTION**

We retain Non-PII for use to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests for no more than eighteen (18) months. Aggregate reports generated from such data may be retained for a longer period.

**MISCELLANEOUS**

**Children’s Privacy.**  
ValueClick Media is very sensitive to the issue of the privacy rights or children. ValueClick Media Websites and services generally are neither developed for, nor directed at, children.

**Your Representations.**  
YOU UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ANY DISPUTE OVER PRIVACY IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND APPLICABLE SITE TERMS AND CONDITIONS. You also agree that you have provided notice to, and obtained consent from, any third party individuals whose Information you supply to us with regard to: (a) the purposes for which such third party's Information has been collected; (b) the intended recipients or categories of recipients of the third party's Information; (c) which of the third party's data are obligatory and which data, if any, are voluntary; and (d) how the third party can access and, if necessary, rectify the data held about them. It is the express wish of the parties that the Privacy Policy and all related documents have been drawn up in the English language and that the English version of this Privacy Policy shall be the sole version used in interpreting and enforcing this Privacy Policy. C'est la volonté expresse des parties que la présente convention ainsi que les documents qui s'y rattachent soient rédigés en anglais.
